Good news, everyone.
I've invented a device, which allows you
to operate equipment from great distances.
I call it the Finglonger.
Observe.
And... Here we go...
There.
Pretty long, eh?
Yeah, it's really long
but what did you just turn on with it?
Oh, that's just the What-If machine
I invented.
You pose it a "what if" question
and it generates a video
simulation of what would happen.
- Does it really work?
- Of course it works.
It's just not very long.
Ooh, ooh! I want to axe it a question.
As a robot living among humans
I've never really felt accepted at parties
or nude beaches.
So, I've always secretly wondered...
What if I was 500 feet tall?
Let's watch, shall we?
My work here is done.
I'm so lonely since I came to the future.
Will you be my friend?
Ow!
Ohh!
Who are you?
I'm a big robot and I want a big cereal.
You, too? Will you be my friend?
Put her there, pal.
I meant your wallet.
Three, two, one, zero.
Yeah, that calms the shakes.
Hey!
Okay, okay, come on now.
Stop! The robot's not your enemy.
He's just a poor, misunderstood...
Well, there goes the neighborhood.
There goes another neighborhood.
We're jerked.
Nothing can stop a monster that big.
Nothing except an even
equally big monster.
This is a chance to try out
my experimental enlarging ray,
but we'll need a guinea pig.
What's this?
Two meals in one week?
- Got you!
- Sucker!
Friends, help! A guinea pig tricked me.
What?
So, now Zoidberg is big, huh?
That's more like it.
Who's intimidating who now, big city?
Hello, Mr. Chase Manhattan Bank.
Deny my credit card application, will you?
Ah, the famed Apollo Theater.
Boo me off stage on open-mike night?
I'll show you.
Hey, I called this city.
Quit touching my stuff.
Tell it to the claw.
Bite my colossal metal ass.
Who wants lobster bisque?
- Hey, Bender.
- Huh?
Want to make Shrinky Dinks?
Who put this in here?
No!
Are you people satisfied?
This gentle visitor is dying
and we'll never even know why he came.
I'll... Tell you...
with my final breath.
I came here with a simple dream...
A dream of killing all humans
and this is how it must end?
Who's the real
seven-billion-ton robot monster here?
Not... I.
Good night, sweet prince.
Interesting stuff.
Stay tuned for more:
Well, Leela,
care to give the what-if machine a whirl?
Maybe later.
I mean, I don't know what to ask about.
Come on, woman, just pick something.
Yeah, be more impulsive, like this.
Go, man, go.
I can be really impulsive.
It just takes me awhile.
All right, Professor, let's do it.
Make that machine
show me what would happen
if I was a little more impulsive.
Just a little.
Not too much.
Hey, guys, look what I bought
on a wild impulse...
New boots.
They're like my old ones
but with a crazy green stripe. Whoo!
Never know what I'm going to do next.
Leela, could you come
in here for a moment?
I have something important to tell you.
I can't live forever and I need an heir...
Someone to spend my vast riches
and take care of my man-eating anteaters
when I'm gone.
The others simply aren't
levelheaded enough.
They're too impulsive... not like you.
Not like old, predictable,
dull-as-dishwater Leela.
Hello? New boots.
That's why I've made you my sole heir.
The day I die,
you'll be a very wealthy woman.
Oh, my, yes... Incredibly wealthy.
The day I die...
Because you're so un-impulsive.
- Hi-ya!
- Oh!
You've killed me!
Oh, God, what have I done?
I just told you.
You've killed me!
Okay, just try to be nonchalant.
All right, so you're nonchalant.
Quit rubbing our noses in it.
Sweet giant anteater of Santa Anita!
The professor's been eaten
by giant anteaters!
What?
If you ask me, it's mighty suspicious.
I'm going to call the police...
Right after I flush some things.
Police. Bah! Nosy meddlers.
It so happens I have
mail-order degrees
in Murderology and Murderonomy.
Zoidberg is afoot.
Perhaps the professor's
files can clear things up.
Let's see, citation for public nudity,
conspiracy to commit public nudity.
Ah-ha! A new will naming...
you as his sole heir!
That doesn't prove I killed him.
It's a video will.
It shows you killing him.
Hi-ya!
All right, anteater number one,
who are you protecting?
Is it anteater number two?
Don't stick your tongue out at me.
I need a name.
What? How do you spell that?
What are you hacking off?
Is it my torso? It is! My precious torso!
Hermes, quiet. I'm deducing things.
What do you got? Disposal trouble?
No! Everything's just...
Sure is shocking about the professor.
And now Hermes is mysteriously missing.
Anyhow, it doesn't affect me, Bender.
Hey, what's this?
Hermes' dreadlocks? And his arm?
Leela, I'm shocked.
Food goes in the disposal.
Hair and flesh go in the trash.
I'm sorry. I couldn't stop.
Well, wait.
Don't you care that I murdered Hermes?
Not even a little.
There's nothing wrong with murder
just as long as you let
Bender wet his beak.
You're blackmailing me?
Blackmail is such an ugly word.
I prefer extortion.
The "X" makes it sound cool.
Please, I'm made of metal.
Like you're really going
to hurt me with...
Hey, what are you doing
with that microwave?
Okay, that's it.
No more killing.
Next time you feel like killing,
just have a stick of gum.
Now to dispose of the body.
Honk, honk.
Wow. Sporty go-cart, Leela.
So hip and sexy.
Not like you at all.
Do you have any gum?
No.
Ah! The gang's all here.
Who are you?
Scruffy, the janitor.
I've never seen you before.
I've never seen you before, neither.
Quiet, please.
I've called you all here to the parlor
to watch as I gradually solve the crime.
One of the people in this room
is a big murderer.
You see, the killer left one fatal clue...
This boot print on
the professor's lab coat.
Couldn't be me.
I never wear boots.
See?
Ew! What smells like boot feet?
This is preposterous.
Obviously, the murderer is...
My next clue came at 4:15
when the clock stopped
and another came two hours later, at 4:15
when I discovered the murdered body
of Amy's dead, deceased corpse.
Scruffy knows who killed them people.
In Scruffy's opinion, it were...
So... It's just as I suspected all along.
The crime is unsolvable.
Huh?
A letter from Bender, my good friend.
"Dear Dr. Jerkberg,
"if you're reading this, I'm already dead.
"The person who killed me was... was..."
My God. It can't be.
The murderer. It was...
I'm bored.
You're boring, Zoidberg.
I'm going to go watch TV.
Could you get the lights on your way out?
- Whatcha eating?
- Lobster.
- You want some?
- Sure.
You know, I think I finally figured out
what's behind all these mysterious deaths.
Really?
Was Planet Express built
on an Indian graveyard?
- No.
- No?
- Then... Then...
It was you.
I don't know what came over me.
I killed one person on impulse.
Then I had to kill another and another.
Well, that covers
the first three killings.
And now, to make sure you won't talk...
I'm going to have to do
something really impulsive.
So, Fry...
What do you think of the impulsive new me?
I like it.
Good, now let me just get the lights.
I really like it.
Who else has a question
for the What-If machine?
Scruffy? Fry?
I have a question.
What if Bender was really giant?
You idiot, we already saw that.
I know, I liked it.
I want to see it again.
We're not seeing it again.
Ask something less stupid.
All right, how about this?
What if I never fell
into that freezer doodle
and came to the future jiggy?
That question is less stupid,
though you asked it in
a profoundly stupid way.
What would happen if Fry
never came to the future?
Hello!
Pizza delivery for...
I.C. Wiener?
Oh, crud.
Here's to another lousy millennium.
Ow!
I should have left you
floating in the toilet. Oh!
What is it?
It appears that the very fabric
of space-time has ripped.
Hey, look, an ugly, scared guy. Boo!
Who are you monsters?
Is one of you I.C. Wiener?
If that's his pizza,
than I'm Icy whatever.
You believe me about the monsters,
right, Mr. Panucci?
There's only three real monsters, kid...
Dracula, Blacula and Son of Kong.
Now, quit picking your nose
and knead that dough.
Hey, the usual, Professor Hawking?
No, today I'd like something good.
Hawking, you're all right.
I'll make you the usual.
Hey, Stephen Hawking.
Aren't you that physicist
that invented gravity?
Sure, why not?
Let me ask you something.
Has anyone ever discovered
a hole in nothing with monsters in it?
'Cause if I'm the first,
I want them to call it a Fry hole.
There is nothing to be concerned about.
I must go. There is much to do.
Hey, Hawking, your pizza's ready.
Toss it in the garbage.
There he is. Seize him.
Who said that?
Hey! Hey! Ow!
Who are you people?
I'm Al Gore, and these
are my vice-presidential action rangers,
a group of top nerds whose sole duty
is to prevent disruptions
in the space-time continuum.
I thought your sole duty was to cast
the tie-breaking vote in the senate.
That, and protect
the space-time continuum.
Read the constitution.
Hmm. So I guess
you'll want to see my Fry hole.
Very much so, but first,
meet the action rangers.
You already know Stephen Hawking.
Also with us are Nichelle Nichols,
A.K.A. Commander Uhura.
Incoming transmission
from MCI One-Rate department.
It sounds like a limited-time offer.
Tell them I'm in the tub.
To my left, you'll recognize Gary Gygax,
inventor of Dungeons & Dragons.
Greetings. It's a... pleasure to meet you.
And our summer intern, Deep Blue.
The world's foremost
chess-playing computer.
Bishop to knight four.
Not all missions can
be solved with chess, Deep Blue.
Someday you'll understand that.
Where am I, anyway?
You're traveling in a specially equipped
terrestrial transport module.
A school bus.
So what do you nerds want?
It's about that rip
in space-time that you saw.
I call it a Hawking hole.
No fair. I saw it first.
Who is The Journal of Quantum Physics
going to believe?
Mr. Fry, the time disruption
indicates that some event
was supposed to happen,
but didn't due to a quantum fluctuation.
That's why we had to beat you
with tennis rackets.
If we don't go back there
and make the event happen
the entire universe will be destroyed
and as an environmentalist,
I'm against that.
So then my chair tilted back
and I almost fell
into this freezer thingy.
I call it a Hawking chamber.
But instead of falling in
and getting frozen,
I missed and wanged my head.
Well, it's obvious
what should have happened.
That wang to the head
should have killed you.
What?
Let's finish the job.
No, wait! There must be a peaceful...
- Hold him down.
- Check.
Ow!
Something's wrong. Murder isn't working
and that's all we're good at.
Let's try something else.
Maybe we should...
Put the dice away before I take them away.
Wait, I'm getting an idea.
What if Fry was supposed to get frozen?
Yes.
Shove him in the tube.
It was my idea.
Hey, there he is again
and he brought nerds.
Take this!
Get in the tube, dummy.
We only have a few seconds
before the universe is destroyed.
All right, but I need a weapon
to fight off drunken robots
when I wake up.
Here, take my plus-one mace.
Okay, here I go.
You fool! You foolish fool!
Eh. What's the worst thing
that can happen?
Great.
The entire universe was destroyed.
Destroyed? Then where are we now?
I don't know, but I can darn well tell you
where we're not... the universe.
Eternity with nerds.
It's the Pasadena Star Trek
convention all over again.
Anyone want to play Dungeons & Dragons
for the next quadrillion years?
- Yes, please.
- Sure.
Pawn to rook eight.
I'm a tenth-level vice president.
That story was preposterous.
Stephen Hawking in a pizzeria.
This thing isn't worth
the gold it's made of.
Anyway, "The Thing Longer"
seems to be a rousing success.
Good work.
Right on, Professor.
So that's what things would be like
if I'd invented the Finlonger.
A man can dream, though.
A man can dream.